Kei Imada

500 College Ave - Swarthmore PA 19081 - 206-380-3855 (cell) - kimada1 (at) swarthmore.edu GitHub: keikun555 – Website: keikun555.github.io - LinkedIn: kei-imada

WHO AM I?

Full stack developer, systems research assistant, and teaching assistant for computer science and mathematics. Fluent in Python, C, OpenMPI, CUDA, and Japanese. Has multiple experiences in managing projects while also being a full stack developer for tools which helped thousands of clients. A rising Senior with a 3.9 GPA at Swarthmore College studying computer science and mathematics.

EDUCATION

Swarthmore College

August 2016 - May 2020

Bachelor of Arts with dual majors in Computer Science and Mathematics:

Cumulative 3.9 GPA Major 3.9 GPA

Relevant Coursework: Networks, Parallel and Distributed Computing, Algorithms, Natural Language Processing, Programming Languages, Real Analysis, Modern Algebra, Several Variable Calculus, Basic Differential Equations, Honors Linear Algebra

Skills: Python, C, C++, React, Typescript, MPI, CUDA, Bash and Linux (CentOS), Git, OCaml, SQL, Analysis, Japanese, Chinese, Singing

EXPERIENCE

Pure Storage

Mountain View. CA

Software Engineer Intern June 2019 - August 2019 Implemented the web tool that would support engineers in diagnosing SSD drive failure escalations for over 50,000 WSSD drives

- Reduced guery time by 30% by introducing a SQL database that stores previous responses from Amazon Redshift gueries
- Designed the front end using React and Typescript, with ag-grid, highcharts, and react-select as core components

Swarthmore College Computer Science

Swarthmore, PA

Network RAM Research Assistant

June 2018 - December 2018

- Employed machine learning analysis methods on system statistics to predict when the system is about to swap to disk
- Headed the development of the user level policy infrastructure in C for the NSwap network RAM implementation
- Reduced the runtime of memory intensive benchmarks by 99% and their swap disk usage by 97%

Swarthmore College Computer Science

Swarthmore, PA

Peer Mentor for "Data Structures and Algorithms" and "Introduction to Computer Systems"

January 2017 - December 2018

- Assist computer science professors in lectures and help students learn concepts in data structures, algorithms, and systems
- Lead weekly support sessions to clarify class material and provide lab assistance to students
- Mentor students through structure, logic, and syntax errors while teaching debugging techniques
- Communicate with students, professors, and other peer mentors to explain difficult concepts in clear, concise ways

Swarthmore College Computer Society

Swarthmore, PA

Staff

September 2017 - Present

- Collaborate with other SCCS members to develop various web tools for the Swarthmore College community
- Administer SCCS-run servers and troubleshoot outages
- Oversee workshops on topics in technology and computers

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

Swarthmore College

Swarthmore, PA December 2018

SwatPrereqView Devised a website that visualized prerequisites for 1,850 Swarthmore courses with a total of 1,000 prerequisites

- Designed the frontend using Semantic UI and vis.js
- Built the backend with Flask and a parallel Beautiful Soup 4 scraper in Python 3

Swarthmore College Airpool Project Leader Swarthmore, PA

January 2018 - September 2018

- Headed the development team for a website that would help Swarthmore students schedule carpool rides to and from the airport Scheduled more than 150 rides with more than 1,000 views (Swarthmore Facebook page no longer a mess before break)
- Designed the frontend using DataTables, Fullcalendar, JQuery, and Semantic UI
- Implemented the backend with Flask and MySQL with LDAP authentication

Swarthmore College

Swarthmore, PA

Three-Dimensional Fractal Rendering Software on GPU Clusters

April 2018 - May 2018

- Developed a 3D fractal renderer on a GPU cluster using CUDA C/C++ and OpenMPI with Jonah Langlieb and Liam Packer
- Generated a 8192x8192 PNG image of a tenth iteration 3D fractal in 30 seconds using distributed ray marching techniques
- Tested benchmarks of the software on Swarthmore College's commodity computer cluster
- Co-authored a report about the project and its scalability

University of Washington

Seattle, WA

Real-time Butterworth Type Infinite Impulse Response Filtering Python Package

July 2017 - August 2017

- Engineered a real-time Butterworth type signal filtering package in Python that could filter more than 250 kHz in real-time
- Identified and eliminated bottlenecks to increase processing speed by more than 250 times
- Created a wave audio file frequency filtering package using the signal filtering package

Swarthmore College

Swarthmore, PA

TriCo Course Scheduler Project Leader October 2016 - May 2017 Spearheaded the project that would help over 4,000 students schedule their courses out of over 10,000 courses

- Built the backend for the project using Python, developed the frontend with Bootstrap, Fuze is, and DHTMLX
- Helped 1,000 Swarthmore College, Bryn Mawr College, and Haverford College students schedule their courses